Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/prasiddhi (LinkedIn) www.kaggle.com/boardgamefreak/ kernels (Other)

Top Skills

Tableau Machine Learning Python (Programming Language)

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Malayalam (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Serverless Data Analysis with Google BigQuery and Cloud Dataflow

Building Resilient Streaming Systems on Google Cloud Platform

Serverless Machine Learning with Tensorflow on Google Cloud Platform

EY Analytics - Data science - Bronze Leveraging Unstructured Data with Cloud Dataproc on Google Cloud Platform

Prasiddhi Menon

Data Scientist at Google Bengaluru

Summary

I am a Data Scientist with 6 years of experience in Machine Learning, Statistical Modeling, and Business Intelligence with a significant focus on Financial Crimes and Marketing Analytics. My current role at EY Advisory allows me to innovate in the areas of Anomaly Detection and Natural Language Processing in the Financial Services industry. I am also active on Kaggle in order to practice machine learning on other financial use cases (Credit Risk, Financial Distress etc).

Currently, I am leading an engagement with a Fortune 100 financial services organization, headquartered in New York. My team primarily focuses on Customer Due Diligence and Suspicious Activity Monitoring. In addition to this, I also act as a Subject Matter Expert for other EY Analytics teams. I strongly believe in mentoring my juniors and I regularly conduct technical trainings and knowledge transfer sessions for analytics resources across the firm.

Prior to joining EY, I co-founded Allonzy Marketing with a vision of providing small and medium businesses with insights into their customers and transactions. This experience was intense and enlightening, as we built and handled all aspects of a consulting business from scratch - From building our team to filling our sales pipeline.

Previously, I was with Deloitte Consulting as a Business Technology Analyst. I worked with multiple Fortune 100 companies from the Pharmaceutical and Chemical Industry, helping them with Business Warehousing, Reporting, and Forecasting requirements. I primarily worked with clients from Germany and Ireland in this role.

My tech stack primarily comprises of Python, R, and SQL (PostgreSQL and Impala). For Big Data, I am conversant with HiveQL and Pig Latin. I also have hands-on experience on the

Google Cloud Platform primarily in terms of productionizing machine learning pipelines.

Experience

Google

Quantitative Business Analyst April 2020 - Present (5 months)

Quantitative Business Analyst, gSO Analytics and Insights

EY

2 years 10 months

Senior Consultant - Data Science October 2019 - March 2020 (6 months)

As a Senior Consultant with EY, I work with Financial Services Clients in order to automate their Anti Money Laundering processes using Machine Learning.

The Financial Services Industry is highly regulated and risk-averse, which means that a large part of my role involves not only building the machine learning solution, but also ensuring that the model is not a black box and can be explained to non-technical stakeholders.

Lead Consultant - Data Science September 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 1 month) Bangalore

My role at the Anti Money Laundering practice at EY Advisory is to provide Financial Services clients with analytics consulting and implementation services so that they can meet various regulatory requirements.

The majority of my work has been in Credit Risk Scoring. I have led and implemented projects end-to-end, focusing on experiment design for data collection, modeling, and validation.

Additionally, I play the part of a Subject Matter Expert for machine learning (focusing on anomaly detection and natural language processing). In order to enable my team to up-skill, I regularly conduct training sessions for junior analytics consultants.

Consultant - Data Science
June 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 3 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

My role at the Anti Money Laundering practice at EY Advisory is to provide Financial Services clients with analytics consulting and implementation services so that they can meet various regulatory requirements.

My contributions in this role were in the areas of Customer Due Diligence (CDD) and Suspicious Activity Monitoring (SAM).

Suspicious Activity Monitoring primarily involves Anomaly Detection on temporal Financial Transactions data. It also involves customer segmentation tasks, in order to better identify high risk customer segments.

Customer Due Diligence involves analytics-based understanding of how a customer should be categorized in terms of financial risks. I contributed in this area by developing a Natural Language Processing model to classify customer self-written job descriptions to 1 of 32 US Bureau of Labor Statistics Standard Occupation Classes. This is crucial for sanctions screening and automated customer risk profiling.

My solution has been leveraged as an EY standard product offering and upsold to 2 other Financial Services clients.

Allonzy Marketing
Data Scientist
February 2016 - June 2017 (1 year 5 months)
Bangalore

Allonzy Marketing provides Analytics-as-a-Service Solutions, so that raw data can be converted into actionable insights at the click of a button.

I work as a Data Scientist focusing on Marketing Analytics. The product that we are working on is a plug-and-play recommendation engine for eCommerce businesses. I also handled multiple clients from the retail industry, providing marketing analytics services.

Deloitte
Business Technology Analyst
January 2014 - February 2016 (2 years 2 months)
Bangalore, India

I contributed as a Data Analyst responsible for identifying client's Business Warehousing, Reporting, and Forecasting requirements and implementing solutions.

I worked primarily with Pharmaceutical and Chemical industry clients. My projects made heavy use of SAP BI and SAP CRM data, usually involving forecasting of weekly inventories.

I primarily served clients from Germany and Ireland.

Cerner Corporation
Software Engineering Intern
February 2013 - August 2013 (7 months)

Software engineering intern responsible for the enhancement of various pharmacy modules of Cerner's EMR product. In this role, I learnt the agile approach to software development working on the C# (.NET platform)

Education

Manipal Institute of Technology
Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Electronics and Communications
Engineering · (2009 - 2013)

Vidyaniketan Public School (2000 - 2007)